BRYAN PEARSON

PERSONAL INFORMATION

University: University of Central Florida

College Unit: College of Engineering and Computer Science (CECS)

Address: HPA1-111, University of Central Florida

Email: bpearson@knights.ucf.edu

BIOGRAPHY

Bryan Pearson joined the Department of Computer Science at the University of Central Florida as a Ph.D student in August 2018, under the supervision of Dr. Xinwen Fu. He received his B.S. in Computer Science from Stetson University (2014), with minors in Physics and Mathematics.

Bryan's research interests include security and forensics of wireless sensor networks (WSN) and Internet of Things (IoT) systems, networking quality of service (QoS), and IoT scalability. He has been publishing in several conferences and journals including IEEE International Conference on Communications, SoutheastCon, INFOCOM, and MDPI Sensors.

EDUCATION

University of Central Florida

August 2018 - Present

Ph.D in Computer Science

Focus: Internet of Things (IoT) security Advisors: Dr. Cliff Zou & Dr. Xinwen Fu

Stetson University

May 2018 GPA: 3.507 / 4.000

B.S. in Computer Science Minors in Math and Physics

Advisor: Dr. Daniel Plante

RESEARCH INTERESTS

- IoT security and forensics
- Applications and solutions of WSN and IoT
- $\bullet\,$ Networking and computer systems QoS
- Light cryptography implementation and optimizations

WORK EXPERIENCE

Graduate Assistant August 2018 - Present

Florida IT Pathways to Success (Flit-Path)

Graduate Research Assistant

August 2018 - August 2019

University of Central Florida, Department of Computer Science

Instructor

June 2017 - July 2018

ID Tech Camps

Clerical Assistant

May 2017 - June 2018

Stetson University, Departments of English/Computer Science

SCHOLARSHIPS AND GRANTS

University of Central Florida

Graduate Presentation FellowshipSpring 2020IEEE ICC NSF Student Travel GrantApril 2019Graduate Presentation FellowshipFebruary 2019

B. Pearson 1

Flit-Path NSF Grant	August 2018
Stetson University Presidential Scholarship Federal Pell Grant Bright Futures FASA	August 2014 - May 2018 August 2014 - May 2018 August 2014 - May 2018
ACADEMIC ACTIVITIES	
Committee Membership	
1. Program Committee, Consortium for Computing Sciences in Colleges (CCSC SE)	2020
2. Web Chair (Organizing Committee), SecureComm	2019
Refereed Journal Papers	
1. IEEE Internet of Things Journal (IoT-J)	2021
2. IEEE Internet of Things Journal (IoT-J)	2020
3. IEEE Internet of Things Journal (IoT-J)	2019
Refereed Conference Papers	

August 2018

2021

2020

2020

NOTABLE PROJECTS

Graduate ORC Doctoral Fellowship

MosquittoByte: Fuzzing MQTT Message Brokers

3. Consortium for Computing Sciences in Colleges (CCSC SE)

- This project tries to find vulnerabilities in MQTT brokers using a mutation-based fuzzer. The fuzzer starts with a corpus of valid MQTT packets and applies various fuzzing strategies until the broker crashes.
- Implements a "pseudo-genetic" fuzzing algorithm which tweaks its parameters based on anomalous output and network responses from the broker.
- Written in Python 3.
- So far the fuzzer has discovered vulnerabilities in two popular MQTT brokers.

1. IEEE International Conference on Distributed Computing Systems (ICDCS)

2. IEEE International Conference on Parallel and Distributed Systems (ICPADS)

• This project is part of a course at UCF for the term Spring 2021. It is still in development.

SIC²: Securing MCU Based IoT Devices with Low-cost Crypto Coprocessors

- We demonstrate how the popular ESP32 platform is vulnerable to format string attacks, and how these attacks can be used to compromise private data which is used in the application
- As a general defense, we propose a framework which pairs MCU based IoT devices with the cryptographic coprocessors, which offer secure key storage and secure execution environment
- Proof-of-concept: ESP-WROOM-32 with ATECC608A
- More information: https://bpearson.net/papers/ICPADS_2020_Camera_Ready.pdf

STAIR: Smart Air Network

- This project plots ambient particulate matter, CO2, air pressure, temperature, and humidity data from sensors onto a map. Our current deployment of devices are built using the SAML11 microcontroller.
- My contributions to this project include integration with Amazon Web Services such as IoT Core (communication from/to sensors), Lambda (payload decoding), DynamoDB (data storage), EC2 (web server), and CodePipeline (CI/CD).
- Publication is forthcoming. The website is available here: http://3.85.149.13/.
- Source code available upon request.

B. Pearson 2

IoT Security Hands-on Laboratory

- We develop a low-cost platform with an industrial grade MCU ESP32 equipped with a crypto co-processor ATECC608A and create teaching materials including labs and case studies for IoT security education.
- Labs include: JTAG hacking, JTAG defense, UART hacking, UART defense, flash ethical hacking, secure key storage, secure booting, network attack, network defense, and secure over-the-air update.
- More information: https://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-3-030-43605-6_17
- Sample lab: http://cyberforensic.net/labs/iot_secure_key_storage/secure_key_storage.html

PUBLICATIONS

- 1. M. Cash, S. Wang, B. Pearson, Q. Zhou, X. Fu. On Automating BACnet Device Discovery and Property Identification. In proceedings of IEEE International Conference on Communications (ICC), Montreal. June 2021.
- 2. Z. Ling, R. Liu, Y. Zhang, K. Jia, B. Pearson, X. Fu, L. Junzhou. Prison Break of Android Reflection Restriction and Defense. In proceedings of IEEE International Conference on Computer Communications (INFOCOM) 2021. Virtual conference. May 2021.
- 3. B. Pearson, C. Zou, Y. Zhang, Z. Ling, X. Fu. SIC²: Securing Microcontroller Based IoT Devices with Low-cost Crypto Coprocessors. In proceedings of IEEE International Conference on Parallel and Distributed Systems (ICPADS) 2020. Hong Kong. Dec. 2020.
- 4. B. Pearson, D. Plante. Secure Deployment of Containerized IoT Systems. In proceedings of IEEE SoutheastCon 2020. Raleigh, North Carolina. Mar. 2020.
- 5. Y. Zhang, J. Weng, Z. Ling, B. Pearson, X. Fu. BLESS: A BLE Application Security Scanning Framework. In proceedings of IEEE INFOCOM 2020 - IEEE Conference on Computer Communications (INFOCOM). Beijing, China. Apr. 2020.
- 6. B. Pearson, L. Luo, C. Zou, J. Brian, Y. Jin, X. Fu. Building a Low-cost and State-of-the-art IoT Security Hands-on Laboratory. 2nd IFIP Internation Internet of Things (IoT) Conference. Oct. 31-Nov. 1, 2019. (Invited Paper.)
- 7. C. Gao, L. Luo, Y. Zhang, B. Pearson, X. Fu. Microcontroller Based IoT System Firmware Security: Case Studies. In proceedings of IEEE International Conference on Industrial Internet (ICII), Orlando, FL, Nov. 2019. (Best Paper Award.)
- 8. B. Pearson, L. Luo, Y. Zhang, R. Dey, Z. Ling, M. Bassiouni, and X. Fu. On Misconception of Hardware and Cost in IoT Security and Privacy. In proceedings of IEEE International Conference on Communications (ICC), Shanghai, China, May 2019.
- 9. L. Luo, Y. Zhang, B. Pearson, Z. Ling, H. Yu, and X. Fu. On the Security and Data Integrity of Low-Cost Sensor Networks for Air Quality Monitoring. Sensors (Basel). Dec. 2018.
- 10. N. Domingo, B. Pearson, and Y. Jin. Exploitations of Wireless Interfaces Via Network Scanning. In proceedings of IEEE International Conference on Computing, Networking and Communications (ICNC), Santa Clara, CA, 2017.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: C, Python, Java, R, PHP, JavaScript, MatLab

Software: Arduino IDE, ESP-IDF, MatLab, Splunk, Wireshark, Mongoose OS, AWS, Google Cloud, Microsot Azure, Node.js, Apache, Nginx, Spark, Docker, Kubernetes

REFERENCES

Dr. Xinwen Fu (Primary Advisor)

Associate Professor of Computer Science

University of Central Florida Email: xinwenfu@ucf.edu

Dr. Cliff Zou (Co-advisor)

Associate Professor of Computer Science

Email: changchun.zou@ucf.edu

University of Central Florida

B. Pearson 3